CHIRAG BARANDA

Technical support specialist, Full-time

A Graduate student in Computer system technician Software support, with experience and extensive education in technical support. A fast learner with multitasking skills. Experience as a technical specialist-L2 with strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experienced in software development. Strong work ethic in a team or individual setting to drive product success.

mail.info.chirag96@gmail.com	\searrow
+1-(289)-922-8270	
Burlington, Canada	0
chiragbarandaofficial.wordpress.com	
linkedin.com/in/chiragbaranda	in

github.com/chiragmb96 🚺

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Specialist

Canadian Tire Financial Services

01/2019 - 08/2019

Welland, ON

Experience

- Experienced as Level 2 Desk-side Support
- Experience of ticketing service Service Now
- Developed batch and power-shell scripts
- Software Deployment Using SCCM and Manual method
- Advanced Troubleshooting and Solution Documentation
- Worked in project for windows migration and testing
- Experienced working in Office 365 Migration

Store AssociatePatel Computers

05/2016 - 06/2017

Ahmedabad, G.J. INDIA

Responsibilities

- Strong understanding of desktop operating systems, routinely thinks outside the box to solve problems quickly
- Provide technical assistance and resolution as necessary
- Set up new computer systems and perform routine maintenance
- Ensure that Internet security software is updated and running properly
- Test and implement new software programs for the company

Application DeveloperBruminds Technocrats Pvt. Ltd.

08/2016 - 03/2017

Ahmedabad, INDIA

Responsibilities

- Plan, test, and implement various Web-based applications using Java- servlet, Hibernate and JSP, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL Server
- Developed a browser-based management system, allowing various documents to be placed in Windows Explorer interface folders.
- Developed security administration applications, controlling authority levels in database transactions and minimizing safety problems; partially implemented using Java.
- OTP implementation for self-Authentication

EDUCATION

Diploma in Computer system technician - Software support

Mohawk College

09/2017 – 12/2019

Hamilton, ON

Computer Engineering L.D. College of Engineering

08/2013 - 03/2017



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Python, C/C++, C# .Net, MVC/WEB-API, Basic React.js, Basic Wordpress, Basic Go

Operating system

Windows 7/8/10, Windows 7/10 server, Linux Ubuntu

Server Management

Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager(SCCM)

Database

SQL Server, Oracle, MS Access, Basic Vpshere & MS Azure

API used

Bing Map, Yelp. Basic REST

Software Applications

Net Beans , Sublime Text, Visual Studio, SQL Server, Katalon Recorder, Microsoft Office, Draw.io

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Batch Scripts (01/2019 - 08/2019)

- Force Group Policy update , Renaming Devices on server
- Install/uninstall list of software on single click of script
- Make a list of installed software from device on server
- Resetting internet connection, Map network Drives
- PS Script :Pin-Unpin Applications from Desktop/Start Menu for set of applications

Mohawk College (09/2017 - 12/2019)

- Developed Windows applications using C#, Java, python
- Worked with Microsoft tools i.e Microsoft word/excel-VBA/Access/project
- Website Testing using Katalon Recorder
- Java Data structure and algorithm, Battleship strategy improvement

Tourist Helper Web App (09/2019 - 12/2019)

- A responsive web application designed for a tourist using following technologies - HTML | Bootstraps | Bing-Map | Yelp API
- Application allow user to find various places as per search criteria i.e Restaurants, Accommodation, Events, Hospitals and Police Station
- Application was designed to rate various places, like and comment from Tourist

Paint Program - A Desktop Application (Java)

- User can draw different objects by choosing a color and setting stroke width. Select, undo and delete operations can be applied on those objects.
- This application is a cumulative activity that will draw on many of the features of Java, OOP concepts and critical thinking.
- It was created using exception handling, event handlers, graphics, Java FX GUI components, inheritance, array list, polymorphism and implementation of both abstract and concrete classes.

Money-on-Click Web Application (08/2016 - 03/2017)

- A web application developed using Java-hibernate, Html,CSS, JSP, and Javascript. A single platform where there are two types of user for this web application. One who wants to pay and get work done and another who wants to work and get paid.
- Application has one time password implementation for new user registration and forgot password for both email and phone number